newyorkjobs.com 2001-06-12

# ComputerJobs.com - Privacy Statement

   **INFORMATION COLLECTION**

For all processes that require information collection, ComputerJobs.com is committed to providing the highest level of security and privacy for IT professionals and employers. 

We use various methods to collect information on our site, such as registration forms, contests, surveys, request forms, contact us, and mail-to's. These registration forms are linked to ComputerJobs.com mailing lists and require users to give contact information (such as name and email address). We use this contact information to send users information about our company and its products and services. The information may also be used to contact site visitors by email for marketing purposes. Registered users can opt-out of receiving email marketing communications through the opt-out function available in each email message delivered from ComputerJobs.com. Once a user has completed the opt-out process, they will be removed from ComputerJobs.com email marketing mailing list. 

ComputerJobs.com collects system-related information, such as IP address, browser type, and operating system type, and uses it for system administration purposes. This information helps diagnose problems with our servers, monitor traffic patterns, and site usage. System information also assists us in identifying the most popular areas of our site, so we can continue to deliver content that is important and relevant to our users. 

       **Information Collected from IT Professionals:**

> * **User Registration**  
>  To register to use the Web site for creating an online resume, creating a Consultant’s Corner profile, applying for a Direct Connect position, or using Power Search, IT professionals must complete our personalization profile. The registration process requests the following information: 
> 
>   1. Required information: First and last name, email address, password of their own creation, zip code, at least one skill or certification, and how they heard about us.   
> 
>   2. Optional information: Password hint, if they would like to participate in Job Matching, and if they would like to receive emails of jobs that match their skill set. 
> 

> * **Resume Registration**  
>  To place a resume online, IT professionals must complete our resume registration. The resume registration process requests the following information: 
> 
>   1. Required Information: First and last name, state, at least one skill or certification, a brief career summary, availability, willing to work location, citizenship information, how they heard about us, and the amount of time that subscribing companies should have access to their resume.   
> 
>   2. Optional Information: Address, city, zip code, country of residence, home and work phone numbers, email address, best time to contact, additional skills/certifications and how much experience they have in those, desired position/objective, education history, Web resume URL, preferred work location, employment type, travel considerations, security clearance, polygraph certification, resume blocking options, use of other employment Web sites information, which type of clients should have access to their resume, and if they want an email reminder before their resume expires. 
> 

> * **Consultant's Corner Profile**  
>  To place a Consultant’s Corner profile on our site, IT professionals must complete the profile form. The process requests the following information: 
> 
>   1. Required information: Before completing the profile, IT professionals must confirm that they are available for work on a contract status and that they are eligible to work in the United States. They must also provide contractor title; first and last names; city, state, and zip code of residence; email address; years in business; number of employees; major skill category they wish to be listed under; at least one specific skill; and a list of services they provide.   
> 
>   2. Optional information: Company name, address, phone number, fax number, company URL, indication if the company is incorporated, the number of clients they have, additional specific skills, certifications, references, notes, willingness to travel, rate, how clients are billed, preferred work location, how they found our site, preferred project description, and if they wish to be auto-logged in to Consultant’s Corner instead of being directed to the My Career page at login. 
> 

> * **Direct Connect Online Applications**  
>  The apply online process requests the following information from IT professionals: 
> 
>   1. Required information: First and last name; zip code; email address; password that the user creates; work status; how the user heard about us; desired salary or rate; willingness to relocate; willingness to travel; at least one skill category, subskill, and months experience; street address; city; state; availability; phone number; work history (at least one company name, city, state, last title held, start and end dates, and skills used); education history (at least one institution, city, state, major, degree, and year of graduation); and security clearance information.   
> 
>   2. Optional information: User may attach a resume, enter the URL for a Web resume, country of residence, call notes, details of work history, and accreditation and certification information. 
> 

> * **Feedback**  
>  ComputerJobs.com encourages feedback from IT professionals. The feedback enables us to continually improve our products and services. All information received through the feedback process becomes the property of ComputerJobs.com and may be used in press materials and advertisements. 
> * **Message Boards**  
>  ComputerJobs.com makes message boards available to its users. Any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information. Users should exercise caution when disclosing personal information to any message board. 

       **Information Collected from IT Employers:**

> * **Client Registration**  
>  To fully utilize the services offered by ComputerJobs.com, employers must complete our client registration. The 'Join Us' client registration form requests the following information: 
> 
>   1. Required Information: Company name, city, state, zip code, type of company, contact name, email address, number of IT recruiters, number of IT openings to fill on a monthly basis, how did you hear about our site.   
> 
>   2. Optional Information: Contact person's title, company URL, phone number, fax number, number of IT employees, states where client is most interested in advertising, comments and suggestions. 
> 

> * **Financial Transactions**  
>  Credit card transactions are processed through CyberCash, a leading third-party credit card processing company. CyberCash only uses your information to complete the appropriate transactions. ComputerJobs.com stores the first two and last four digits of your credit card to complete the verification and approval process. Your entire credit card number is not stored on any ComputerJobs.com system. 
> * **Feedback**  
>  ComputerJobs.com encourages feedback from all employers. All exchange of information between ComputerJobs.com and our employers is confidential unless written permission to use such information for another purpose is given. 

   **INFORMATION USE**

ComputerJobs.com is committed to safeguarding your personal information. We take this responsibility very seriously and are continuously looking for improved methods to ensure privacy and security. 

> **Use of Information Collected from IT Professionals**
> 
> COMPUTERJOBS.COM DOES NOT SELL YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION TO ANYONE. It is important to note that information provided in the resume registration process is completely available to subscribing employers. Our employers sign contracts that legally prohibit them from redistributing ComputerJobs.com information without consent. 
> 
> Information provided in the Consultant's Corner registration process is online, public information. 
> 
> Information provided in the Direct Connect registration process is not available to all employers, but is available to a career specialist employed by ComputerJobs.com. 
> 
> Internally, ComputerJobs.com uses your personal information for validation purposes only. To predict broad trends about our Web site, we request general or generic input from our users in a clearly identifiable fashion, such as our Salary Survey or the Question of the Day. 
> 
> **Use of Information Collected from Employers**
> 
> Information collected from employers is not shared with third parties. Employer information is used for contact and billing purposes only. Because of the nature of the ComputerJobs.com Web site, any information that is included on a job listing must be considered public information. ComputerJobs.com provides an anonymous job posting option to exclude contact or company information from public view. IT professionals can only respond to anonymous job postings through an online form which prevents them from knowing the identity of the anonymous job poster.
